Contact

gil.fernandes@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/gil-palma-fernandes (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

HBase

Apache Pig

MapReduce

Languages

German

English

Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)

Spanish (Limited Working)

French (Professional Working)

Certifications

Algorithms on Strings
Intro to Descriptive Statistics

Front-End Web Development with React

Algorithmic Toolbox

Gil Fernandes

Software Engineer at Onepoint Consulting

London Area, United Kingdom

Summary

A Software Engineer and data scientist with over 23 years of professional experience in different companies. I spent a good part of my professional career working in projects related to the aviation industry and the rest as developer in Talend and Java based projects.

In 2019 I commenced my learning on Artificial Intelligence and Deep Learning and related technologies and participated in several Kaggle competitions.

I also contribute regularly several open source components to Talend Exchange.

I dedicate my weekends to my pet projects for UK charities which promote well-being and meditation.

Experience

Onepoint Consulting
Software Engineer and Data Scientist
July 2007 - Present (16 years)
London, England, United Kingdom

Senior Software Engineer

About Onepoint:

Onepoint was established in 2005 in London to specialise in enterprise architecture consulting and open source solutions.

Based out of London and Pune, today we help our worldwide clients assess, define, and deliver successful digital initiatives by applying design thinking and the latest innovations in Al, cloud, data, sensors, low code, and more.

We are proud to be called trusted partners by our clients. We love to provide value in whatever we do.

Our core service areas are Do Data Better, Innovate with Al & more, and Solve with Design Thinking. We welcome complex digital problems. Drop me a direct message on LinkedIn or get in touch through our website at onepointItd.com.

Vaultium
External developer
2009 - June 2011 (2 years)

Frequentis
Software Developer
October 2009 - January 2011 (1 year 4 months)
Software Developer in the EAD project

One Point IT Consulting Pvt. Ltd.

Software Developer

2007 - July 2007 (less than a year)

SSLPost Mail Gateway implementation using Spring Roo and Subetha.

Frequentis Software developer September 2001 - July 2007 (5 years 11 months)

I have worked for almost 6 years in the development of the EAD (European Airspace Information Services Database) programme. I helped to develop the user management and a proprietary SSO system for the EAD.

Education

Universität für Musik und darstellende Kunst Wien Bachelor degree in musical education science, Musical education science · (1988 - 1993)

Deutsche Schule in Lissabon (1980 - 1988)